MARK LAWRENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEAD

+64 21 071-7247 - mailto:markl.nz@hotmail.com - http://markl.nz - http://github.com/marklnz

I have over 18 years of experience in the IT industry, working for a range of organizations. I am a senior architect with a broad range of experience and technical knowledge in the Microsoft architecture and development domains. I have worked on many projects ranging in size and complexity, for a number of different business sectors. Outside of work, I have a keen interest in aviation and flight simulation, and also enjoy playing guitar in my spare time.

EXPERIENCE

DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEAD: Eyede Solutions Limited, Jan 2013 – present

Team lead, architect and software engineer.

- Responsible for leading in-house software development team, working predominantly with Microsoft technologies on complex web based applications.
- Oversee and collaborate with the other senior developers in developing Eyede's next generation web application architecture using Angular, TypeScript (JavaScript), HTML 5 and CSS 3.
- Assisted in building developer tooling for the next generation web architecture with Node.js, Gulp, Bower and Karma.
- Full stack software developer and architect.
- Managed Eyede's internal TFS server deployment, and developed the DevOps processes and procedures, using TFS, Team Build and OctopusDeploy
- Migrated Eyede's internal TFS based DevOps tooling to Visual Studio Online, with Git for version control, using Team Build v.Next for build.
- Developed mobile app prototypes using Xamarin's cross platform mobile development tools, as well as the Cordova app development framework.

SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT: Optimation Limited, Jul 2007 – Jan 2013

Senior member of Optimation's C# development team.

- Built Optimation's reusable .net software architecture and reference implementation.
- Served as technical lead and architect on .net projects for Optimation.
- Administered and managed Optimation's Team Foundation Server environment, including process customization and end user training.
- Developed solutions, and effort estimates in pre-sales and contract negotiation situations.
- Performed technical architecture and delivery reviews for a number of customers.

SENIOR DEVELOPER/ARCHITECT: EDS New Zealand Limited, Apr 1998 – Jul 2007

Architect, senior developer and project team lead.

- Served as Applications Architect for an account with a major New Zealand government client. Was responsible for overall application design on a range of applications, covering technologies ranging from VB6 through to .net 3.0, in a Service Oriented Architecture environment.
- Contributed to numerous pre-sales efforts, in both New Zealand and throughout the Asia Pacific region.
- Worked with other members of the architecture team, as well as with customer representatives, in defining and evolving an Enterprise Application Architecture for a major New Zealand government client.

- Served as EDS New Zealand's Team Foundation Server expert. Responsibilities ranged from general TFS administration through to customization of tools and processes, as well as user support.
- Composed EDS' global C# coding standards document, as well as acting as reviewer for the global VB.Net coding standards.
- Lead designer and developer on an internal project to build a "request for service" portal, later adopted by EDS sites and customers across the Asia Pacific region.
- Lead developer on a multi-year document imaging and data capture project for another major New Zealand government department.
- Aided in establishing a graduate recruitment program, through conducting interviews of applicants and mentoring successful candidates within the team.

ANALYST/PROGRAMMER: Queensland Rail, Brisbane, Australia. May 1997—Mar 1998 Senior Software Developer

- Initially joined to work on mainframe projects using COBOL and DB2.
- Worked on a range of windows based and client/server software projects, using Visual Basic and a 4GL programming language.
- Provided second level helpdesk support for users writing macros for Microsoft Office Applications.

ANALYST/PROGRAMMER: EDS New Zealand Limited. Jul 1994–Feb 1997

- Joined EDS as a graduate mainframe programmer.
- Worked as part of the team supporting one of EDS' major banking clients.
- Developed enhancements and new functionality using CICS COBOL and Assembler language.

SKILLS

C# AND .Net: C#, .Net Core CLR, ASP.Net, ASP.Net 5, ASP.Net MVC, Entity Framework, Web API, WCF, ASP.Net Web Services, Windows Forms, WPF, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, MS Test, NUnit, XUnit.

WEB DEVELOPMENT: HTML, CSS, JSON, jQuery, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Development, Node.js, Angular.js, Gulp.

DATA STORAGE/DATA ACCESS: Microsoft SQL Server, SQL, XML, ER Data Modelling.

DEV OPS: Team Foundation Server, Visual Studio Online, Visual Studio 2015 Team Build, Octopus Deploy, GitHub, Git, Continuous Integration, Continuous Deployment, Automated testing.

MOBILE APP DEVELOPMENT: Xamarin Studio, Xamarin Forms, Kendo UI, Android Studio, Cordova.

DEVELOPMENT METHODOLOGIES: Scrum, CMMI, MSF

ARCHITECTURE: TOGAF, SOA, Solution Architecture, Integration Technologies.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: Victoria University of Wellington (Wellington, New Zealand), 1989-1993

• Graduated with a major in Geography having initially studied Computer Science.